Finding Aid for Constance E. Cumbey papers, 1920-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical Files
  - Group 2
    - Whole Life Expo (Box 76)
    - Wicca (Box 76)
    - The Elie Wiesel Foundation for Humanity (Box 76)
    - Simon Wiesenthal Center (Box 76)
    - Stuart Wilde [Transcendence] (Box 76)
    - The Wilderness Society (Box 76)
    - David Wilkerson (Box 76)
    - Lindsey Williams (Box 76)
    - Betty Willman (incl. correspondence and clippings regarding Psychology of Sex Professor Barry Singer and lawsuit), 3 folders (Box 76)
    - Betty Willman, Creative Initiative / Beyond War (Box 76)
    - John Wimber (Box 76)
    - Windstar Foundation [John Denver] (incl. photograph) (Box 76)
    - Oprah Winfrey (Box 76)
    - Dr. Ernst Winter (Box 76)
    - Win-Win Philosophies (Box 77)
    - Wisconsin (Box 77)
    - Wisconsin, Green Bay (Box 77)
    - Wisconsin, Madison (Box 77)
    - Wisconsin, Milwaukee (Box 77)
    - Witchcraft, 3 folders (Box 77)
    - Witness Lee (Box 77)
    - Wittenberg Door (Box 77)
    - Women's Liberation (Box 77)
    - Wally Wood, Christian News Network / Services (Box 77)
    - Word Books, Waco, Texas (Box 77)
    - World Bank (Box 77)
    - World Citizens (Box 77)
    - World Conservation Strategy (Box 77)
    - World Constitution and Parliament Association (Box 77)
    - World Council of Churches, 2 folders (Box 77)
    - World Economic Review (Box 77)
    - World Federalists (Box 77)
    - World Food Authority (Box 77)
    - World Future Society (see Barbara Marx Hubbard) (Box 78)
    - World Future Society, 3 folders (Box 78)
    - World Health Organization (Box 78)
    - World Instant of Cooperation, 3 folders (Box 78)
    - World Market / Common Market (Box 78)
    - World Policy Institute (Institute for World Order) (Box 78)
    - World Relief (Box 78)
    - World Teacher Trust (Box 78)
    - World University (Box 78)
    - World Unity Forum (Box 78)
    - World Vision (Box 78)
    - Worldwide Church of God (Box 78)
    - World Wildlife Fund (Box 78)
    - Wycliffe Bible Translators (Box 78)
    - Wyoming (Box 78)
    - Xenia, Ohio (Box 78)
    - Yahweh, Congregation of (Box 78)
    - Yasodhara Ashram (Box 78)
    - Year of Jubilee (Box 78)
    - Year of the Bible (Box 78)
    - John Howard Yoder (Box 78)
    - Youth for Christ (Box 78)
    - Yoga (Box 78)
    - Youth With A Mission (Box 78)
    - Yuppies (Box 78)
    - Yurika Foods (Box 78)
    - Zen Buddhism (Box 78)
    - Zero Population Growth (Box 78)
    - Zig Ziglar (Box 78)
    - Zionist (Box 78)
    - Zondervan (Box 78)
  - Group 3
    This topical files subseries is the smallest but with the most currently dated material (5 linear feet; bulk dates 1990-2000). File headings are similar to the other two groups.
    - Abortion (Box 79)
    - The Academy, Ohio 1991 (Box 79)
    - AD2000 and Beyond Movement [printed 1999 www.ad2000.org] (Box 79)
    - AIDS (Box 79)
    - Gary Allen (Box 79)
    - Alternative Press (Box 79)
    - Americanism (Box 79)
    - Americans for Cooperative America 1992 (Box 79)
    - Animal Rights (Box 79)
    - Amnesty International (Box 79)
    - Anarchy (Box 79)
    - Anti-Abortion (Box 79)
    - Anti-Catholicism (Box 79)
    - Anti-Cults (Box 79)
    - Anti-Nuclear Movement (Box 79)
    - Anti-Semitism (Box 79)
    - Apologetic Research Commission 1991 (Box 79)
    - Apostasy (Box 79)
    - Apple Farm Papers (Box 79)
    - Aquarian Education Group (Box 79)
    - Arcane School 2003 (Box 79)
    - Aryan Nations, 2 folders (Box 79)
    - Astrology (Box 79)
    - Avatar Journal 1989 (Box 79)
    - John Barela (Box 79)
    - Sam Blumenfeld (Box 79)
    - Joan Borsenko (Box 79)
    - William Branham An Exposition of the Church of the Ages (Box 79)
    - Brazil (Box 79)
    - Bill Britton pamphlets (Box 79)
    - Harald Bredesen (Box 79)
    - Pat Buchanan (Box 79)
    - George Bush (Box 79)
    - Cashless Society (Box 79)
    - Catalyst magazine 1989 (Box 79)
    - Catholicism (Box 79)
    - Center for Democratic Research (Box 79)
    - Channeling 1992 (Box 79)
    - Charismatic Renewal (Box 79)
    - Chicago, Illinois (Box 79)
    - Children's Amendment (Box 79)
    - Children's Literature (Box 79)
    - Child Welfare, Michigan [printed 199, www.michiganbrief.org] (Box 79)
    - China 2001 (Box 79)
    - Christian Coalition 1997 (Box 79)
    - The Christian Conscience magazine (Box 79)
    - Christian Identity Movement (Box 79)
    - Christianity and Crisis magazine 1986-1987 (Box 79)
    - The Christian Century 1985 (Box 79)
    - The Christian World Report 1990 (Box 79)
    - Christendon College (Box 79)
    - Christian Science (Box 79)
    - CIA, Central Intelligence Agency 1995 (Box 79)
    - Bill Clinton (Box 79)
    - Club of Rome (Box 79)
    - Coalition on Revival 1986 (Box 79)
    - Communes, [printed 1998 www.splcenter.org/klanwatch] (Box 79)
    - Communities: Journal of Cooperation 1983-1985 (Box 79)
    - Concentration Camps, United States and Canada [printed 1998 www.inforamp.net/~jwhitley] (Box 79)
    - Constitution, United States 1991-1992 (Box 79)
    - Constitutional Convention (Box 79)
    - Coptic Fellowship (Box 79)
    - Covert Action Information Bulletin 1991 (Box 79)
    - Creationism (Box 79)
    - Benjamin Crème (Box 79)
    - Criminal Law (Box 79)
    - Dennis Cuddy (Box 79)
    - Ioan Culinau (Box 79)
    - Dead Sea Scrolls 1989 (Box 79)
    - Death Control (Box 79)
    - Distant Drums (Box 79)
    - Tom Donahue (Box 79)
    - Dowsing (Box 79)
    - Druids (Box 79)
    - David Duke (Box 79)
    - Duns Scotive (Box 79)
    - Dusten, John W. "Future Feudalism: Prophetic Symbol -- Historic Form" [mss.] (Box 79)
    - Earth Day (Box 79)
    - Earth Summit 1992 (Box 79)
    - Eastern Europe (Box 79)
    - Ecumenical Movement (Box 79)
    - Education (Box 79)
    - England (Box 80)
    - Environmental Movement (Box 80)
    - Ephesians 5:11 newsletter (Box 80)
    - Eternal Life 1992 (Box 80)
    - Eugene, Oregon (Box 80)
    - Euthanasia (Box 80)
    - Fascism (Box 80)
    - Jerry Falwell (Box 80)
    - Family (Box 80)
    - Fatima Crusader magazine (Box 80)
    - Fayetteville, Georgia (Box 80)
    - Federal Programs (Box 80)
    - Fellowship in Prayer (Box 80)
    - Feminist Majority Coalition (Box 80)
    - Feminist Movement (Box 80)
    - Feminist Theology -- Anti-Semitism (Box 80)
    - Marilyn Ferguson (Box 80)
    - The Fetzer Foundation (Box 80)
    - Findohorn Foundation (Box 80)
    - Focus on the Family (Box 80)
    - Foundation, A Magazine for Biblical Fundamentalism 1991 (Box 80)
    - Matthew Fox (Box 80)
    - Freemasonry (Box 80)
    - Newt Gingrich (Box 80)
    - Global Day of Action, Seattle, Washington 1992 (Box 80)
    - Global Family Products 1988 (Box 80)
    - Global Harvest Ministries (Box 80)
    - Gnosis Magazine 1993 (Box 80)
    - Goddess Worship (Box 80)
    - Grey Brotherhood (Box 80)
    - Bo Gritz (Box 80)
    - Guardian Angels (Box 80)
    - Guiding Light Readings (Box 80)
    - Rev. Franklin Hall, "Atomic Power With God Thru Fasting and Prayer," 1946 (Box 80)
    - Steven Halpern (Box 80)
    - Harmonic Convergence (Box 80)
    - Yisrayl Hawkins (Box 80)
    - Kathleen Hayes (Box 80)
    - Kathleen Hayes and Samantha Smith, "Grave New World," 1986 (Box 80)
    - Hazardous Waste [incl. Oakland County, Michigan petition] (Box 80)
    - Herbs (Box 80)
    - Heritage Foundation (Box 80)
    - Hermeneutics 1992 (Box 80)
    - Holistic Education Review 1991 (Box 80)
    - Homosexuality (Box 80)
    - Hopi Prophecies (Box 80)
    - Human Life International (Box 80)
    - Hypnosis (Box 80)
    - Immortality (Box 80)
    - Individual Sovereignty Society (Box 80)
    - Infinity Institute (Box 80)
    - Intuition (Box 80)
    - Iowa (Box 80)
    - Islam (Box 80)
    - Japan (Box 80)
    - Bob Jones University (Box 80)
    - Journaling (Box 80)
    - Judaism (Box 80)
    - Jung (Box 80)
    - Kansas City (Box 80)
    - King James Bible (Box 80)
    - Doug Krieger (Box 80)
    - Jiddu Krishnamurti (Box 80)
    - Ku Klux Klan (Box 80)
    - Viktoras Kuluinskas, "Survival Into the 21st Century" (Box 80)
    - Tim LaHaye (Box 80)
    - La Iglesia Lukumi Babalu Ave. (Box 80)
    - Peter LaLonde (Box 80)
    - Lapeer, Michigan (Box 80)
    - Lyndon H. LaRouche, Jr. (Box 81)
    - Norman Lear (Box 81)
    - C.S. Lewis 1989, 1995 (Box 81)
    - Liberty Corners (Box 81)
    - Liberty Lobby (Box 81)
    - Libertarianism (Box 81)
    - Life-Study Fellowship (Box 81)
    - Hal Lindsay (Box 81)
    - Tony Liuzzo (Box 81)
    - The Llewellyn New Times newspaper (Box 81)
    - Los Angeles, California (Box 81)
    - Lost Tribes (Box 81)
    - The Love Tapes (Box 81)
    - The Lubavitch Movement (Box 81)
    - Lucis Trust, 2 folders (Box 81)
    - Shirley MacLaine (Box 81)
    - Macrobiotics (Box 81)
    - Mafia (Box 81)
    - Magic (Box 81)
    - Manifest Sons of God (Box 81)
    - Dorothy Margraf (Box 81)
    - Maitreyan Movements (Box 81)
    - Marginalizing (Box 81)
    - Marion Movement (Box 81)
    - Rev. Daniel Markham (Box 81)
    - Tex Marrs (Box 81)
    - Malachi Martin (Box 81)
    - Marty Martin (Box 81)
    - Massage Therapy (Box 81)
    - Master Mind Groups (Box 81)
    - Roy Masters (Box 81)
    - Donald McAlvany (Box 81)
    - James McKeever (Box 81)
    - Pauline McPherson (Box 81)
    - Meditation (Box 81)
    - Mediation Machines (Box 81)
    - Meditation magazine (Box 81)
    - Medjugorje (Box 81)
    - Men's Groups (Box 81)
    - Messiah Lutheran (Box 81)
    - Messianism (Box 81)
    - Metaphysical Movements (Box 81)
    - Mexico (Box 81)
    - Michigan (Box 81)
    - Michigan Alliance Families (Box 81)
    - Michigan Coalition of Unregistered Churches (Box 81)
    - Michigan Education Association (Box 81)
    - Michigan Family Forum 1992 (Box 81)
    - Middle Earth (Box 81)
    - Midnight Call (Box 81)
    - Mockers and Scoffers (Box 81)
    - Military -- Christian Organizations (Box 81)
    - Military -- United States (Box 81)
    - Ken Miller (Box 81)
    - Mind Control (Box 81)
    - Mind Science (Box 81)
    - Tom Monaghan (Box 81)
    - Stanley Monaghan (Box 81)
    - Moody magazine 1992 (Box 81)
    - Moonies (Box 81)
    - Robert Morey (Box 81)
    - Mormons (Box 81)
    - Mother Angelica (Box 81)
    - Mount Weather (Box 81)
    - Movement for a New Society (Box 81)
    - Robert Muller (Box 81)
    - Eustace Mullins (Box 81)
    - Multi-Faith Resources (Box 81)
    - John Naisbit (Box 81)
    - National Association of Environmental Law Societies 1989 (Box 81)
    - N.C.E.A., National Catholic Education Association (Box 81)
    - National Council of Churches (Box 81)
    - National ID (Box 81)
    - Native Americans (Box 81)
    - Natural Resources Defense Council (Box 81)
    - Natural Disasters (Box 81)
    - Nav Press (Box 81)
    - Nazism (Box 81)
    - Neo-Nazism (Box 81)
    - Nestle Boycott (Box 81)
    - Networking Institute (Box 81)
    - Network of Youth Ministries (Box 81)
    - Neuro Linguistic Programming 1989 (Box 81)
    - Neuropsychology (Box 81)
    - New Age Book Reviews (Box 81)
    - New Age Books (Box 81)
    - New Age Catalogs (Box 81)
    - New Age Catholics (Box 81)
    - New Age Correspondence (Box 81)
    - New Age Disinformation (Box 81)
    - New Age Home Economics (Box 82)
    - New Age Humor (Box 82)
    - New Age Journal (Box 82)
    - New Age Learning (Box 82)
    - New Age Movement (Box 82)
    - New Age Music (Box 82)
    - New Age Networking (Box 82)
    - New Consciousness Network (Box 82)
    - New Dimensions Radio 1991 (Box 82)
    - New Group of World Servers (Box 82)
    - New Right (Box 82)
    - New Thought Alliance (Box 82)
    - The New Times 1991 (Box 82)
    - The New World Order (Box 82)
    - Noetic Sciences (Box 82)
    - Northville, Michigan (Box 82)
    - The Nonviolent Activist 1986 (Box 82)
    - NATO, North Atlantic Treaty Organization (Box 82)
    - Nuclear Weapons Sites (Box 82)
    - Oasis Center (Box 82)
    - Omega Institute for Holistic Studies 1990-1991 (Box 82)
    - Omega New-Age Directory (Box 82)
    - Online BBS 1991 (Box 82)
    - Ontario (Box 82)
    - Operation Rescue (Box 82)
    - Opus Dei (Box 82)
    - Order of the Golden Dawn (Box 82)
    - The Order of the Star 1929 (Box 82)
    - Oryana Food Cooperative (Box 82)
    - Bill Owens (Box 82)
    - Father Mitchell Pacwa (Box 82)
    - Paganism (Box 82)
    - Parents as Teachers 1990-1992 (Box 82)
    - Earl Parks (Box 82)
    - Parliament of World Religions (Box 82)
    - Pastors (Box 82)
    - Peace Academy (Box 82)
    - Peace and Dignity Journeys 1992 (Box 82)
    - Peace Links (Box 82)
    - Peace Movement (Box 82)
    - Rev. Norman Vincent Peale (Box 82)
    - H. Ross Perot (Box 82)
    - Father Edward Perrone [Sex Education in Capac Community Schools] (Box 82)
    - Phenome News 1989 (Box 82)
    - The Plan (Box 82)
    - Planetary Association for Clean Energy (Box 82)
    - Planned Parenthood (Box 82)
    - Points of Light (Box 82)
    - Pope John Paul II (Box 82)
    - Population Research Institute 1991 (Box 82)
    - Populist Party (Box 82)
    - Portland, Oregon (Box 82)
    - Potentials Unlimited Tapes (Box 82)
    - Ezra Pound (Box 82)
    - Hugh Prather (Box 82)
    - Presbyterians (Box 82)
    - John Randolph Pierce (Box 82)
    - Privatization (Box 82)
    - Probe Ministries (Box 82)
    - Pro-family Forum (Box 82)
    - Promise Keepers (Box 82)
    - Prophet Movement (Box 82)
    - Prosperity Doctrine (Box 82)
    - Prout Movement (Box 82)
    - Psychic Dictatorship in America, Gerald B. Byron (Box 82)
    - Psychic Healers (Box 82)
    - Pyschotronics Association (Box 82)
    - Psychology (Box 82)
    - Putting People First (Box 82)
    - Quantum Physics (Box 82)
    - Quest Program (Box 82)
    - Rainbow Search Newsletter (Box 82)
    - Bhagwan Shree Rajneesh Meditation Center (Box 82)
    - Ayn Rand Institute (Box 82)
    - Rap Music (Box 82)
    - Reconstructionists (Box 82)
    - Reconstruction, Crosswinds: The Reformation Digest (Box 82)
    - Reincarnation (Box 82)
    - Regent College (Box 82)
    - Religious Liberty (Box 82)
    - Religious Prosecution (Box 82)
    - Revelation, A Journal of the Ageless Wisdom and The New Age Teachings 1985-1986 (Box 82)
    - Cecil Rhodes (Box 82)
    - Jeremy Rifkin [printed 1998 www.paranoia.com] (Box 82)
    - Ritual Murders (Box 82)
    - Pat Robertson (Box 82)
    - Rockefeller (Box 82)
    - Rockford Conference (Box 82)
    - Roman Catholic Faithful, Inc. [Catholicism and homosexuality] 2000 (Box 82)
    - The Rosicrucian Fellowship (Box 82)
    - Theodore Roszak (Box 82)
    - Rosemary Ruether (Box 82)
    - Russia (Box 82)
    - Saint Herman of Alaska Brotherhood (Box 82)
    - Sane/Freeze Activist, Campaign for Global Security, Michigan 1990 (Box 82)
    - Mark Satin (Box 82)
    - Satanism (Box 82)
    - Phyllis Schlafly (Box 82)
    - School of Metaphysics (Box 82)
    - Robert Schuller (Box 82)
    - Fred Schultz (Box 83)
    - Science Fiction (Box 83)
    - Science of Mind (Box 83)
    - Scientology (Box 83)
    - Seattle, Washington (Box 83)
    - Secular Humanism (Box 83)
    - Sedona (Box 83)
    - Seminars -- New Age (Box 83)
    - Seventh Day Adventists (Box 83)
    - Ron Sider (Box 83)
    - Sikhism 1991-1994 (Box 83)
    - 666 (Box 83)
    - Skull and Bones (Box 83)
    - Small Group Church Work (Box 83)
    - Social Credit Movement (Box 83)
    - Society of Emissaries 1985 (Box 83)
    - Society of Prayer for World Peace (Box 83)
    - Software -- New Age (Box 83)
    - Javier Solano [incl. photographs] (Box 83)
    - Sons of Liberty (Box 83)
    - Soundworks (Box 83)
    - South End Press 1991 (Box 83)
    - Southwest Radio Church 1977-1987 (Box 83)
    - Soviet-American (Box 83)
    - Space Bridges (Box 83)
    - Spiritual Communism (Box 83)
    - Star Blazers scouting organization (Box 83)
    - Donna Steichen (Box 83)
    - Rudolf Steiner (Box 83)
    - Swami Dayananda Saraswati (Box 83)
    - Tara Center (Box 83)
    - Tarot Cards (Box 83)
    - Theosophy 1938-1943 (Box 83)
    - Theosophy -- Lucifer (Box 83)
    - Theosophical Order of Service Peace Department and Circles for Peace 1991-1992 (Box 83)
    - Temple of Understanding (Box 83)
    - Tradition, Family, and Property (Box 83)
    - Transcendental Meditation (Box 83)
    - Treaties (Box 83)
    - The Trilateral Commission (Box 83)
    - Trinity Publishing (Box 83)
    - Ted Turner (Box 83)
    - UFO Cults (Box 83)
    - Unitarian Universalism (Box 83)
    - United Methodist Church [printed 1999] (Box 83)
    - Unity Center (Box 83)
    - United Nations (Box 83)
    - Unregistered Churches (Box 83)
    - Utah (Box 83)
    - Gerald Vano, "The Unification of Christianity and Evolution," [mss.] (Box 83)
    - James Vassilos (Box 83)
    - Violent Attacks (Box 83)
    - Waldorf School, Massachusetts (Box 83)
    - George H. Warnock, "Feed My Sheep" [mss.] (Box 83)
    - WEU Council of Ministers (Box 83)
    - David Wilkerson (Box 83)
    - Wisconsin Report 1989-1991 (Box 83)
    - Wichita (Box 83)
    - Witchcraft (Box 83)
    - World Federalist (Box 83)
    - World Government (Box 83)
    - World Peace (Box 83)
    - www.paranoid.com (Box 83)
    - Z Magazine 1992 (Box 83)
    - Bi D. Zein, "Journeys: A Screenplay" (Box 83)
    - Zionism (Box 83)
- Constance Cumbey Personal
  The Constance Cumbey Personal series (1 linear foot) is divided into five subseries: Correspondence (many of the topical files also contain correspondence); Ephemera, which includes biographical statements, newspaper clippings, and public appearances; Interview Transcripts; Manuscripts; and Publications, which contains the two books that Constance Cumbey wrote about the New Age movement (as well as two foreign language translations), miscellaneous articles and presentations, and her New Age Monitor newsletter.
  - Correspondence
    - "Crank Letters", 2 folders (Box 84)
    - "Encouraging Letters" (Box 84)
    - General Correspondence (Box 84)
    - German Correspondence (in German) (Box 84)
    - Senator Jesse Helms to Bill Thomas regarding "The Hidden Dangers Of The Rainbow" by Constance Cumbey and the Antichrist (Box 84)
  - Ephemera
    - Biographical Statements (incl. photographs) (Box 84)
    - Malcolm X Academy, Warrendale, Michigan, Speech Transcript and Letter to the Detroit Free Press, 1992 (Box 84)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1975-1987 (Box 84)
    - Public Appearances 1982-1992 (Box 84)
  - Interview Transcripts
    - May 1982 The Gary Randall Program (Box 84)
    - February 1983 Eric Pement, Phone Interview (Box 84)
  - Manuscripts
    - Book #2 Drafts (Box 84)
    - Viola Liuzzo Story (Box 84)
    - Manuscripts in Progress (Box 84)
    - Typed Notes Concerning "New Age" Texts (Box 84)
  - Publications
    - "A Planned Deception," Pointe Publishers, contracts and ephemera (Box 84)
    - Book: The Hidden Dangers of the Rainbow 1983 (Box 84)
    - Book: A Planned Deception: The Staging of a New Age Messiah 1985 (Box 84)
    - New Age Writings 1987-1995
      - A "Harmonically Converged Betrayal of the Evangelical Church"-From Gold Lake Ranch Conference Center to AD 2000 and Beyond, 1987 (Box 84)
      - New Age Movement Issues and Practices Discussed in the Bible 1989 (Box 84)
      - Constance Cumbey Blasts Forthcoming CBN Conference on New Age Movement as "Dis-information-Not Information" 1990 (Box 84)
      - Is Hospice Really "Right to Life" or Is it a Vital Part of the Right to Die Movement? 1994 (Box 84)
      - The New World Religion 1994, 1995 (Box 84)
    - Constance Cumbey's New Age Monitor newsletter, 1986-1991 (Box 84)
    - "The Hidden Dangers of the Rainbow" appearances on Christian Bestseller Lists (Box 84)
    - "Regnbuens Skjulte Farer" [Hidden Dangers...] book 1983 (Box 84)
      In Norwegian
    - "Die Sanfte Vergührung" [Hidden Dangers...] book 1983 (Box 84)
      In German
- Other Media
  The Other Media series (3 linear feet) contains CD-ROM's, twenty-six VHS videotapes, and 145 audio cassette tapes. Most of the VHS tapes contain presentations and debates that Cumbey gave and participated in at locations throughout the country during the 1980's where she discussed her books and the New Age Movement. These tapes shed light on why Constance Cumbey spent many years studying the movement and why she views it as a destructive force in Christianity and in modern American society. A number of the tapes are recordings of television programs or local news programs from the 1980's and the early 1990's that discuss New Age themes. Many of these taped television programs contain brief interviews with Cumbey. There are also a few tapes that focus on a debate between Cumbey and Christian Mystic Elizabeth MacDonald Burrows on the topic of religion and the New Age Movement. A majority of the audiocassettes are recordings of Law Talk, a call-in radio program hosted by Constance Cumbey, which contains discussion of both legal and religious topics. The CD-ROM contains a powerpoint presentation made by Cumbey that highlights the political activity of European Union Secretary-General Javier Solana. She makes clear her opinion that Solana has ties to the New World Order by discussing his Marxist past, his attacks against the religion of conviction, and his plans to achieve a stronger and dominant Europe.
  - CD-ROM
    - Law Talk audio February 27, 2004, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 85)
    - Javier Solana 2004, 2 optical disks CDs (Box 85)
  - VHS Tapes
    - Channel 7 Local News 3/10/1993, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (Tape contains news stories on Malcolm X Academy, terrorism, NAFTA, and Rodney King)
      (tape no. 1)
    - Christian Research Institute Conference, Cumbey discusses the New Age Movement 1983, 2 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 2 and 3)
    - Jay Cole (Mission Ministries, Arkansas), "Speaking Out" radio and TV spots regarding AIDS, homosexuals, abortion, New Age, etc., 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 4)
    - Combined tape that includes Kent Schroder's presentation on the Summer Institute of Linguistics and Technology, and Jay Gary's presentation on AD 2000, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 5)
    - Combined tape that includes Pecos River Learning Center Tape, Geraldo Rivera "John Rogers-MISA" and the Governor's Conference on Education 1989, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 6)
    - Combined tape that includes The 700 Club TV Program with Pat Robertson and Jay Gary's presentation on the Power of AD 2000, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 7)
    - Combined tape: television programs "Straight Talk" with Jeffrey Miller and Copeland Ministries 1997, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 8)
    - Conference on New Age Movement, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (Cumbey tells how she discovered the New Age Movement)
      (tape no. 9)
    - Cumbey-Presentation "Apostasy in the Church: Pat Robertson Expose", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 10)
    - Cumbey and Ed Taub Debate 7/7/1990, 1 videotapes VHS (TM), copied (Box 85)
      (tape no. 11)
    - Cumbey debates with Elizabeth Burrows January 1987, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 12)
    - Cumbey-Presentation "Melanin and the Mark of the Beast", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 13)
    - Cumbey-Presentation on the New Age Movement in North Dakota 3/1/1987-3/8/1987, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 14)
    - Cumbey-Presentation on the New Age Movement at the Human-Life International Conference, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 15)
    - Cumbey-Presentation on the New Age Movement in St. Mary's, Kansas 3/12/1988, 1 videotapes VHS (TM), master (Box 85)
      (tape no. 16)
    - Cumbey-Presentation on AD 2000 and the New Age Movement, 3/3/1990, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 85)
      (tape no. 17)